MORTEZA REZANEJAD

PERSONAL

Homepage: https://mrezanejad.github.io/

Email: morteza.rezanejad@utoronto.ca

Address: 521 Sidney Smith Hall, 100 St. George Street, Toronto, Ontario, Canada

GitHub: https://github.com/mrezanejad

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.ca/citations?user=bpj7d8EAAAAJ

Last update of this CV: May 17^{th} , 2021

CURRENT APPOINTMENTS

Postdoctoral Fellow*, University of Toronto

Jan. 2020 - Present

Project title: "Understanding the Principles that Guide the Perceptual Grouping and Organization of Visual Cues in Perception"

Advisors: Professor Dirk Bernhardt-Walther and Professor Michael Gruninger

* University of Toronto Arts & Science Postdoctoral Fellowship Recipient, 2020

Role description: I am leading the Pixels to Propositions (Pix2Props) research team. Our team works on visual perception problems in collaboration with the Department of Computer Science, Psychology, and Mechanical & Industrial Engineering at the University of Toronto.

Advisory Board Member, The Dexign Studio

Sept. 2019 - Present

Role description: I am a scientific advisory board member at the Dexign Studio (https://thedexignstudio.com/) and I am also a cofounder of Penplay (https://penplay.ca/), an ML based iOS game from the dexign studio.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science, McGill University

Sept. 2013 - Oct. 2019

Thesis: "Medial Measures for Recognition, Mapping, and Categorization"

Advisor: Professor Kaleem Siddiqi

Available on Google Books: https://bit.ly/2RkE6MO

Mini-MBA, McGill University

Sept. 2018 - Jan 2019

Executive Development Course (EDC)

I was awarded Clark SELF Scholarship to attend this series of executive development course.

M.Sc. in Computer Science, McGill University

Sept. 2009 - May 2013 *

Thesis: "Flux Graphs for 2D Shape Analysis"

Advisor: Professor Kaleem Siddiqi

Available on McGill's Library: https://bit.ly/3bC7m8q

* I was on a leave of absence from May 2011 to May 2012, working as an iOS developer for Neda Rayaneh.

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering, Sharif University of Technology

Sept. 2005 - July 2009

Thesis: "Online Signature Verification Using Symbiotic Feature Selection" Advisor: Professor Saeed Bagheri Shouraki & Professor Ramin Halavati

Undergraduate Trainee and Research Assistant

Oct. 2007 - Aug. 2009

Computer Vision Group, Institute for Research in Fundamental Science (IPM)

Project title: "Automatic Detection of Melanoma"

Advisor: Professor Mehrdad Shahshahani

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Engineer

July. 2017 - Nov. 2017

Software Group, NeuroRX

Role description: In this project, I worked on an automated quality assessment of Magnetic Resonance Images. I implemented a deep learning based framework that was able to find missing 3D MRI scan slices as well as determining whether a slice is misplaced within the neighboring slices.

iOS Developer

July. 2011 - May 2012

iOS Team, Neda Rayaneh Institute

Role description: I was involved in the development of two iOS-based applications: i) Chare which is a mobile user interface to the first Persian online shopping store, ii) iPersia which is a tourist guide for iPad users who want to access professional photographers' landscapes before visiting a place.

Part-time Software Developer

Sept. 2006 - July 2009

Software Group, Kavosh Com Soroush

Role description: I was part of a project whose goal was to localize a web-based CRM for the Iranian market. We deployed extreme Programming as our development methodology and were successful at localizing several features of the vTiger CRM.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecturer, University of Toronto

May. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Introduction to Image Understanding

Department: Electrical & Computer Engineering Academic Session(s): Summer 2020, Fall 2020

Lecturer, University of Toronto

Jan. 2020 - April 2020

APS 105 - Computer Fundamentals

Department: Electrical & Computer Engineering

Academic Session(s): Winter 2020

Lecturer, McGill University

Sept. 2015 - Jan. 2016

COMP 208 - Computers in Engineering Department: School of Computer Science

Academic Session(s): Fall 2015

Teaching Assistant, McGill University

Jan. 2013 - April 2017

COMP 558 - Computer Vision

Department: School of Computer Science

Academic Session(s): Winter 2017, Winter 2015, Fall 2013, Winter 2013

Teaching Assistant, McGill University

Fall. 2017 - Dec. 2018

ECSE 202 - Introduction to Software Development

Department: Electrical and Computer Engineering

Academic Session(s): Winter 2019, Fall 2018, Winter 2018, Fall 2017

Teaching Assistant, McGill University

Jan. 2014 - Dec. 2018

COMP 208 - Computers in Engineering

Department: School of Computer Science

 $A cademic\ Session(s):\ Fall\ 2019,\ Winter\ 2019,\ Fall\ 2018,\ Winter\ 2018,\ Fall\ 2017,\ Fall\ 2016,\ Winter\ 2016,\ Fall\ 2019,\ Fall\ 2019,\$

Fall 2015, Fall 2014, and Winter 2014

Teaching Assistant, Sharif University of Technology

CE 121 - Electrical Circuits

Department: Computer Engineering Academic Session(s): Winter 2007

Teaching Assistant, Sharif University of Technology

Jan. 2007 - Apr. 2007

Jan. 2008 - Apr. 2008

CE 115b - Discrete Mathematics Department: Computer Engineering Academic Session(s): Winter 2007

Teaching Assistant, Sharif University of Technology

Sept. 2008 - Dec. 2008

MATH 22071 - Numerical Computing Department: Mathematical Science Academic Session(s): Fall 2008

Teaching Assistant, Sharif University of Technology

Sept. 2007 - Dec. 2007

MATH 22046 - Calculus I

Department: Mathematical Science Academic Session(s): Fall 2007

PUBLICATIONS

Journal articles

- 1. S.A. McDowell, R.B. Luo, A. Arabzadeh, S. Doré, N.C. Bennett, V. Breton, E. Karimi, M. Rezanejad, R.R. Yang, K.D. Lach, M.S. Issac, 2021. Neutrophil oxidative stress mediates obesity-associated vascular dysfunction and metastatic transmigration. Nature Cancer (2021), pp.1-18.
- 2. J. Wilder, M. Rezanejad, S. Dickinson, K. Siddiqi, A. Jepson and D. Bernhardt-Walther. Local contour symmetry facilitates scene categorization. Cognition 182 (2019): 307-317.
- 3. M. Rezanejad and K. Siddiqi. View Sphere Partitioning via Flux Graphs Boosts Recognition from Sparse Views. Frontiers in ICT: Computer Image Analysis 2 (2015) 24.

Conference articles and abstracts

- 4. C-O Dufresne Camaro, M. Rezanejad, S. Tsogkas, K Siddiqi, and S. Dickinson. Appearance Shock Grammar for Fast Medial. To appear in *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition*, Seattle WA, 2020 (CVPR 2020).
- 5. M. Rezanejad, G. Downs, J. Wilder, D. Bernhardt-Walther, A. Jepson, S. Dickinson, and K. Siddiqi. Medial Axis Based Contour Salience for Scene Categorization. *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition*, Long Beach CA, 2020 (CVPR 2019).
- M. Rezanejad, G. Downs, J. Wilder, D. Bernhardt-Walther, A. Jepson, S. Dickinson, and K. Siddiqi. Perceptually Weighted Contours For CNN-Based Scene Categorization. Conference on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience, Berlin, Germany, September 2019.
- 7. J. Wilder, M. Rezanejad, K. Siddiqi, A. Jepson, S. Dickinson, and D. Bernhardt-Walther. Local contour symmetry facilitates the neural representation of scene categories in the PPA. *Conference on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience*, Berlin, Germany, September 2019.
- 8. M. Rezanejad, G. Downs, J. Wilder, D. Bernhardt-Walther, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson and K. Siddiqi. Perceptual grouping aids recognition of line drawings of scenes by CNNs. *Vision Science Society*, St. Pete Beach, United States, 2019.
- 9. J. Wilder, M. Rezanejad, K. Siddiqi, A. Jepson, S. Dickinson, and D. Bernhardt-Walther. The neural basis of local contour symmetry in scene perception. *Vision Science Society*, St. Pete Beach, United States, 2019.

- 10. J. Wilder⁺, **M. Rezanejad**⁺, K. Siddiqi, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson and D. Bernhardt-Walther. Measuring Local Symmetry in Real-World Scenes. In *Journal of Vision*, 18 (2018) 749–749.

 +: Equal contribution.
- 11. M. Rezanejad, J. Wilder, K. Siddiqi, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson, and D. Bernhardt-Walther. Measuring Local Symmetry in Real-World Scenes Using Derivatives of the Medial Axis Radius Function. In *Computational and Mathematical Models in Vision (MODVIS)*, St. Pete Beach, United States, 2018.
- 12. J. Wilder, M. Rezanejad, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson, K. Siddiqi and D. Bernhardt-Walther. The Perceptual Advantage of Symmetry for Scene Perception. In *Journal of Vision*, 17 (2017) 1091–1091.
- 13. J. Wilder, M. Rezanejad, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson, K. Siddiqi and D. Bernhardt-Walther. The role of symmetry in scene categorization by human observers. In *Computational and Mathematical Models in Vision (MODVIS)*, St. Pete Beach, United States, 2017.
- 14. M. Rezanejad, J. Wilder, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson, D. Bernhardt-Walther and K. Siddiqi. Scoring Scene Symmetry. In *Computational and Mathematical Models in Vision (MODVIS)*, St. Pete Beach, United States, 2017.
- 15. S. Hong, J. Fishbaugh, M. Rezanejad, K. Siddiqi, H. Johnson, J. Paulsen, E. Y. Kim and G. Gerig. Subject-Specific Longitudinal Shape Analysis by Coupling Spatiotemporal Shape Modeling with Medial Analysis. In *Proc SPIE Int Soc Opt Eng*, 10133(2017) 101331A. 28966430[pmid].
- 16. M. Rezanejad, B. Samari, I. Rekleitis, K. Siddiqi and G. Dudek. Robust environment mapping using flux skeletons. In 2015 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), pp. 5700-5705.

Book and book chapters

- 17. M. Rezanejad and K. Siddiqi. Flux graphs for 2D shape analysis. Chapter 3 in *Shape Perception in Human and Computer Vision: An Interdisciplinary Perspective*. Editors: Sven Dickinson and Zygmunt Pizlo, Springer, 2013.
- 18. M. Rezanejad, A. Mokhtarian, M. Zaeri Amirani and M. Mohammadabadi. Mathematics Olympiad in Iran. ISBN: 9789647685962, Publisher: Danesh Pajouhan Javan.

AWARDS AND HONOURS

2021 Elsevier/Vision Research Award

March. 2021

VSS2021, St. Pete Beach, Florida, United States

Arts & Science Postdoctoral Fellowship

March. 2020

University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada

GREAT Travel Award

Sept. 2019

School of Computer Science, McGill University, Montreal, Canada

Mini-MBA Clark SELF Scholarship

Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Desautels Faculty of Management, McGill University, Montreal, Canada

Second Best Poster Award

March 2018

NSERC CREATE Medical Image Analysis - Industrial Partner Day, Montreal, Canada

Grad Excellence Award x 3

July 2015, July 2016, and Jan. 2018

School of Computer Science, McGill University, Montreal, Canada

IEEE RAS/IES IROS Travel Award

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Hamburg, Germany

K40 Tesla GPU Award Oct. 2014

Oct. 2015

NVIDIA Corporation, Santa Clara, USA

McGill Differential Fee Waiver Award x 3 July 2010, July 2013, and July 2014

Faculty of Science, McGill University, Montreal, Canada

National Elite Foundation Award Nov. 2007

Ministry of Education, Tehran, Iran

Ranked 154th in the National University Entrance Examination Aug. 2005

Among more than 400,000 participants, National Organization of Educational Test, Tehran, Iran

Bronze Medal in 22nd Iranian National Mathematics Olympiad Sept. 2004

National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents, Tehran, Iran

Prize winner of the 5th Kharazmi Youth Festival Oct. 2003

Iranian Research Organization for Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Python, C/C++, Java, MATLAB, Objective-C, HTML

Operating Systems Windows, Mac, Linux, iOS, Free BSD, Unix

Frameworks & IDEs Eclipse, PyCharm, vim, xCode, Visual Studio, Keras, Tensorflow,

Robot Operating System (ROS), OpenCV, QT

Typesetting T_EX, L^AT_EX, Microsoft Office

RELEVANT GRADUATE COURSES

Computer Vision Machine Learning

Computer Graphics Advanced Mobile Robotics

Probabilistic Analysis of Algorithms Shape Analysis

Applied Machine Learning (audited)

Matrix Computations

Algorithmic Game Theory Statistical Computer Vision (audited)

PEER REVIEW ACTIVITIES

CVPR (2021)

ICCV (2021)

ECCV Conference (2014)

CCN (2019)

IET Computer Vision (2014)

CRV Conference (2016, 2018, 2019, 2020, & 2021)

SELECTED PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED TALKS

3D Medial Representations for Shape Analysis

CREATE MIA Summer School, Montreal, Canada, May 2016

Object Representation using 2D and 3D Medial Axes

CIM Student Research Showcase, Montreal, Canada, November 2016

The role of symmetry in scene categorization by human observers

CREATE-MIA Retreat, Montreal, Canada, September 2016

Robust Environment Mapping Using Flux Skeletons

IROS Conference, Hamburg, Germany, September 2015

View Sphere Partitioning via Flux Graphs

CIM Student Research Showcase, Montreal, Canada, March 2015

Online Signature Verification Using Genetic Algorithm

Institute For Research in Fundamental Science (IPM), Tehran, Iran, September 2008

Automated Melanoma Recognition Using Computer Generated Features

Institute For Research in Fundamental Science (IPM), Tehran, Iran, May 2008

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English: Fluent, Persian: Native, French: Intermediate, Arabic: Intermediate

MENTORSHIP

 Chandra Gummaluru
 Aug. 2020 - Present

 Sidharth Gupta
 Aug. 2020 - Present

 Ryan Marten
 Aug. 2020 - March 2021

 Amir Mousavi,
 May 2020 - Feb. 2021

 Gabriel Downs*,
 May. 2018 - Dec. 2018

* joint supervision with Professor Kaleem Siddiqi

REFERENCES

Will be provided upon request.